Guide to the records of the Musical Acoustics Research Library (MARL) M1711
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 3. Arthur H. Benade Collection, 1956-1987; 19.182 Linear Feet; Between 1982 and late 1987: After cancer was diagnosed in the fall of 1982, Benade made increased use of detailed projections (with many pages hand-drawn) for many of his lectures. Though casual in appearance, these were planned
  - Writings - Music Acoustics Lectures: Vibrations, Rooms, and Ears; Sound and its Musical Relationships; Rooms, Mikes, and Speakers; Sounds Generated in Wind Instruments; The Brasses; Wind Instruments as Musical Devices; The Woodwinds. Indiana University, NSF Summer Institute: Arthur Benade, Clinician, 1974, (program and lecture notes); The Interaction Between Musical Instrument and the Listener. Lecture for the Social, Cultural, and Technological Connection of Acoustics Conference, Cleveland Ohio, 1975, (program, letters, typescript of abstract, and lecture notes); The Physics of Musical Instrument Sound. Lecture for CWRU: College for a Day, 1978, (announcement, program, and lecture notes); Physics and Music. Lecture for Youngstown State University, 1979, (announcement, newspaper clipping, and lecture notes); Comments on a Paper by Gabi Weinriech. For the ASA Meeting, Atlanta, 1980, (notes and calculations); Honors Examination for Oberlin College, Department of Physics. Prepared by Prof. A. H. Benade, 1985, (typescript, handwritten solutions, and correspondence); Sound Structure in Music, by Robert Erickson. Book review, (typescript), 1974 - 1985 (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Writings - Preliminary materials for Fundamentals of Musical Acoustics, 1979, (letters, annotated typescript, etc.) (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Dissertations - By Benade's Students at Case Western Reserve University: Self Sustained Nonlinear Oscillations of Medium Amplitud in Clarinet-Like Systems, 1971, by Walter Elliott Worman; Reed Resonance Effects on Woodwind Nonlinear Feedback Oscillations, 1978, by Stephen Charles Thompson; Woodwind Tone Acoustics and the Spectrum Transformation Function, 1980, by Douglas Howard Keefe; Intercomponent Energy Exchange and Upstream Downstream Symmetry in Nonlinear Self-Sustained Oscillations of Reed Instruments, 1986, by Peter Lindsey Hoekje; The Perception of Musical Tones in the Statistical Sound Fields of Rooms, 1987, by Ian Morgan Lindevald., 1971-1987 (Box 122)
  - Dissertations - James Murday Senior Thesis Project, (typescript), 1964 (Box 112, Folder 2)
  - Annotated Books on General Acoustics, Physics, and Brass Instruments: Lanczos, Cornelius. Applied Analysis, 1961; Morse, Philip M. Vibration and Sound, 1948; Hadamovsky, Hans. Wiener Bläserstil, 1958; Mahillon, Victor-Charles. Elements D'Acoustique Musicale et Instrumentale, 1984; Benade, Arthur H. Fundamentals of Musical Acoustics, 1976; Benade, Arthur H. Horns, Strings & Harmony, 1960; Baines, Anthony. Musical Instruments Through the Ages, 1961; Menke, Werner. History of the Trumpet of Bach and Händel; Schuller, Gunter. Horn Technique, 1963; Gregory, Robin. The Horn, 1961; Pegge, Morley R. The French Horn, 1960; Wick, Denis. Trombone Technique, 1980 (Box 123)
  - Annotated Books on Wind Instruments: Bate, Philip. The Trumpet and Trombone, 1966; Langwill, Lyndesay G. An Index of Musical Wind-Instrument Makers, 1977; Baines, Anthony. Woodwind Instruments and their History, 1963; Bartolozzi, Bruno. New Sounds for Woodwind, 1967; Nederveen, Cornelis J. Acoustical Aspects of Woodwind Instruments, 1969; Boehm, Theobald. An Essay on the Construction of Flutes, 1882; Boehm, Theobald. The Flute and Flute-Playing in Acoustical, Technical, and Artistic Aspects, 1964; Willman, Robert. The Clarinet and Clarinet Playing, 1954; Rendall, Geoffrey. The Clarinet, 1957; Rendall, Geoffrey. The Clarinet, 1971; Kroll, Oskar. The Clarinet, 1965 (Box 124)
  - Annotated Books on Wind Instruments and General Acoustics: Bate, Philip. The Oboe, 1975; Ventzke, Karl. Boehm-Oboen und die Neueren Französischen Oboen-Systeme, 1969; Goossens, Leon and Roxburgh, Edwin. Oboe, 1977; Langwill, Lyndesay G. The Bassoon and Contrabassoon, 1965; Bate, Philip.The Flute, 1979; The Dayton C. Miller Flute Collection. A Checklist of the Instruments, 1961; R. S. Rockstro, The Flute, 1928; Miller, Dayton C. The Science of Musical Sounds, 1933 (with author's autograph); Lord Rayleigh. Theory of Sound, 1945; Miller, Harry B. Acoustical Measurements. Methods and Instrumentation, 1982 (Box 125)
  - Miscellaneous - Acoustical Society of America Silver Medal in Music Acoustics, Arthur H. Benade, 1984, (publication); Biographical Materials (typescript), 1973 (Box 112, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous - ASA Meeting: Arthur Benade Memorial, May 19. Abstracts of the 13 invited papers, (reprint), 1988 (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous - Anastasio, Angelo and Bussard, Nicholas, Mouth Air Pressure and Intensity Profiles of the Oboe, 1971, (reprint with Benade's annotations); Benade's review for Houtsma's National Science Foundation Grant Proposal, 1976; Notes on Acoustics Written at the IDRS Meeting, Boulder, CO, 1985, (program and handwritten notes, 2 pp.); Workshop on Musical Instrument Construction and Repair. University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI (program, memo, and schedule); Contemporary On Bore Reamers, (notes, graphs, calculations); On James Flanagan's lecture for CWRU Centennial Celebration, 1980, (announcement, letters, Flanagan's biographical sketch, and Benade's notes for introducing Flanagan), 1971-1994 (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous - International Symposium on Musical Acoustics. Proceedings. Icicle Creek, Leavenworth, Washington, (bound volume), 1998 (Box 112)
  - Miscellaneous - 35 mm Slides for Lectures: Clarinet perturbations and spectra, 1979; Clarinet cutoff frequencies; Room acoustics; Tool and jigs; Tubas and other brass instruments, Jack Smith 1981; Oboe reed cavity; Violin octet; Clarinet mouthpiece, reed, and barrel; Clarinet’s angular distribution; Register Holes; Keefe Thesis; Curved ducts; Trumpet Tmc - expt, calc.; Room perception; Normal modes (masses, etc.); Regeneration misc.; Flute spectra; French flute, 1961 and 1965; On the mfl of tone-hole design; On the playing properties of bassoons, 1973, circa 1961-1981 (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - Media - Disc, 45 rpm: Side A: Benade: Wind Instruments and Music Acoustics; Side B: Hutchins: The New Violin Family (Box 126)
  - Media - Reel to Reel Tapes: 1 Hutchins violin family (II), 1968, (5", 3.75 ips, 4 tracks, mono, 14 min.); 2 Contrabassophone from Philip Bate, (5", 7.5 ips, 4 tracks, mono, 10 min); 3 2nd Musical Acoustics Advanced Class, (3", 3.75 ips, 4 tracks, mono, 15 min 30 sec); 4 Ed Tarr and George Kent, 1973, (5", 3.75 ips, 4 tracks, mono, 18 min 9 min); 5 Guitar String Notes Generated, 1974, (5" 7.5 ips, 4 tracks, mono, 6 min); 6 New Violin Family, 1968, (7", 7.75 ips); 19 Musical Acoustics #380, Intro Tape A. Side A: Frequency Experiments, 10 min., Side B: Frequency, Pitch, and Timbre Experiments, 9 min. 30 sec., 1971, (3”, 3.75 ips, 4 tracks, mono); 20 Musical Acoustics #380, Intro Tape B. Side A: Relationship Between Pitch and Loudness, 11 min., Side B: Beats Experiments, 11 min. 30 sec.,1971, (3”, 3.75 ips, 4 tracks, mono); 21 Musical Acoustics #380, Tape 1. Side A: Introduction, 17 min., Side B: Combination Tones (pairs), 15 min. 20 sec., 1971, (3”, 3.75 ips, 4 tracks, mono); 22 Musical Acoustics #380, Tape 2. Side A: Effect of Quadratic Non-Linearity, 16 min. 30 sec., Side B: Effect of Quadratic Non-Linearity, 14 min. 30 sec., 1971, (3”, 3.75 ips, 4 tracks, mono); 23 Musical Acoustics #380, Tape 2A. Side A: Effect of Quadratic Non-Linearity, 16 min. 10 sec., Side B: Effect of Quadratic Non-Linearity, 14 min. 20 sec., 1971, (3”, 3.75 ips, 4 tracks, mono); 24 Musical Acoustics #380, Tape 3. Side A: Relations Between Two Complex Tones, “Soft Music” and “Loud Music”, 7 min. 10 sec., Side B: Relations Between Two Complex Tones, “Soft Music” and “Loud Music”, 7 min. 10 sec., 1971, (3”, 3.75 ips, 4 tracks, mono); 25 Musical Acoustics #380, Tape 4. Side A: Loud Sounds Combined Together, 7 min. 45 sec., Side B: Loud Sounds Combined Together, 4 min. 20 sec., 1971, (3”, 3.75 ips, 4 tracks, mono); 26 Musical Acoustics #380, Tape 5. Side A: Bassoons Tones as Played by John Paterson and Cello-Lecture Demonstration by John Shelling of the Bell Lab, 12 min. 10 sec., Side B: blank, 1971, (3”, 3.75 ips, 4 tracks, mono); 27 Musical Acoustics #380, Tape 6. Side A: Stanesby Recorders (2 Altos, 1 Bass) Recorded in London Aug. 1965, 6 min., Side B: blank, 1971, (3”, 3.75 ips, 4 tracks, mono); 28 Musical Acoustics #380, Tape 7. Side A: Bassoon, 8 min., Side B: Baroque Instruments, 6 min., 1971, (3”, 3.75 ips, 4 tracks, mono), The following tapes are available as compact discs: Tape 2, Contrabassophone from Philip Bate, Tape 3, 2nd Musical Acoustics Advanced Class Tape 4, Ed Tarr and George Kent Tape 5 Guitar String Notes Generated Tape 19 - 28 Musical Acoustics #380 (Box 126)
  - Media - Audio Cassettes: 9a Talk by Benade, maybe at Toronto or Denver, 1967 (?), Side A: 39 min., Side B: 23; 9b Talk by Benade, maybe at Toronto or Denver, 1967 (?), Side A: 37 min., Side B: 15min., 20 sec.; 10A Caussé, Moving Source, Moving Mikes, 1981, Side A: 4 min., Side B: blank; 10B Caussé, Int. and Ext. Bassoon Spectra, 1981, Side A: 10 min., Side B: blank; 10C Tuba with Jack Smith, 1981, Side A: 21 min., Side B: blank; 11 Contrabass Clarinet, Side A: 4 min., Side B: blank; 12 Strange Sounds Lecture, 1974, Side A: 53 min. 7 sec., Side B: blank; 13 Stockholm, Harman Kardon Deck, Side A: blank, Side B: blank; 14 Leblanc, Side A: 35 min., Side B: 10 min.; 15 South Indian Flute, 1977, Side A: 18 min., Side B: blank; 16 Europe Tape, Cobla Music, 1977, Side A: 45 min. Side B: blank; 17 Clarinet Sneaks, 1984, Side A: 26 min., Side B: 28 min.; 18 Clarinet Sneaks (Bundy), 1984, Side A: 9 min., Side B: 31 min.; 30 Tarr-Kent, 1973, Side A: 41 min., Side B: 27 min.; 31 Mouth, Mike, Signal, 1984, Side A: 3 min., Side B: blank; 32 AHB Misc. Clarinet Excerpts, 1983, Side A: 10 min., Side B: 10 min.; 33 Demo Tape: Windway Effects, 1983, Side A: 5 min.; Side B: 32 min.; 34 Trumpet Acoustic Testing, Side A: 15 min., Side B: blank, The following audio cassettes are availble as compact discs: 9a and 9b Talk by Benade, (Toronto?) 12 Strange Sounds Lecture 15 South Indian Flute 16 Europe Tape, Cobla Music (Box 127)
  - Media - Audio Cassettes: 35 Jameson, Musical Degeneration, 1983, Side A: 3 min., Side B: 10 min.; 36 Misc. Demo Sounds and Filtered Voice and Piano, 1984, Side A: 6 min., Side B: blank; 37 Teresa Stich-Randall, Mozart, Side A: 11 min., Side B: blank; 38 Clarinet Sneaks, Side A: 11 min. 20 sec., Side B: 30 min.; 39 Just Scales and Triads,etc., Side A: 11 min., Side B: blank; 40 Airhandling Noise at Strosacker, 1982, Side A: 20min., Side B: blank; 41 Vibes and Baldwin Piano, Side A: 18 min., Side B: 23 min.; 42 Ben Brownstein, violin, 1983, Side A: 30 min. Side B: blank; 43 C Flute, G Flute, Db Piccolo,1985, Side A: 12 min. Side B: blank; 44 Fox Oboe, Lucarelli Reed, etc., 1986, Side A: 8 min., Side B: 25 min.; 45 Chotteau’s Clarinet, Trumpet, etc., 1983, Side A: 26 min. Side B: 27 min.; 46 Wm Hartmann Mis Synthesizer Side A: 30 min. Side B: blank; 47 FSR & Gary Foster to AHB, Side A: 48min. Side B: 33 min.; 48 Bapi Barret, Bassoon,1980, Side A: 15 min. Side B: 8 min.; 49 Clody Duffy, 1973 Side A: 30 min. Side B: 3 min.; 50 Two Lectures, “What Makes Instruments Sing,” Side A: 60 min. Side B: 60 min.; 51 Room Average for Clarinets, 1984, Side A: 16 min. Side B: 2.5 min., The following audio cassette is availabe as compact disc: 50 What Makes Instruments Sing? (Box 128)
  - Media - Audio Cassettes: 52 La Villette Lecture Examples, Side A: 7 min., Side B: blank; 53 Richard Birkemeier Trumpet Spectra, 1983, Side A: 15 min., Side B: 10 min.; 54 Schlueter, Hoekje, and Benade, 1977, Side A: 20 min., Side B: 8 min.; 55 Clarinet Type, Rm 124, 1983, Side A: 25 min. Side B: blank; 56 FSR to AHB, Side A: 30 min. Side B: 20 min.; 57 Shakuhachi, 1983, Side A: 5 min. Side B: 9.25 min.; 58 BCB Flute, Side A: 3 min. Side B: blank; 59 PWW/IAC Demo Tape, 1986, Side A: 6 min., Side B: blank; 60 Wei-Shen Chin, Side A: 30 min. Side B: blank; 61 A. Boulder, English Horn, Side A: 10 min. Side B: blank; 62 Carleen M. Hutchin Violin Family Synthesis, 1968, Side A: 18 min. Side B: blank; Stan Getz,1983, Side A: 4 min., Side B: blank; The Sound of Science, Jim Metzner and Carleen M. Hutchins, 1986, Side A: 10 min. Side B: blank, The following audio cassettes are available as compact discs: 52 La Villette Lecture Examples 57 Shakuhachi or Sound Production in Winds 62 Carleen M. Hutchin Violin Family Synthesis (Box 129)
    Tape 52 La Villette Lecture Examples, see box 107, folder 12 for lecture typescript
  - Media - Video Cassettes: Musical Sound #1 Sound Production 28:38; Musical Sound #2 Sound Emission, 26:15; Musical Sound #3 Physics of Musical Relationships 28:11 (Box 130)
  - Media - Compact Discs, (reformatted reel to reel tapes and audio cassettes): Contrabassophone from Philip Bate; 2nd Musical Acoustics Advanced Class; Ed Tarr and George Kent; Guitar String Notes Generated; Fred Cohen; Banade Lecture, (Toronto?); Strange Sounds Lecture; Comparison of Two South Indian Flutes; Europe Trip, Cobla Music; Musical Acoustics #380; La Villette Lecture Examples; What Makes Instruments Sing?; Shakuhachi or Sound Production in Winds; Carleen M. Hutchins Violin Family Synthesis, La Villette Lecture Examples, see box 107, folder 12 for lecture typescript (Box 126)
    Original missing
    The original reel to reel tape 7" 7.5 ips entitled Fred Cohen is missing
  - Oversize (items identified in their respective folders) (Box 137)
  - Clarinet Mouthpieces and Reeds (Box 136)
  - Additional Research Material from Subsequent Accessions: 2010-191 and 2011-018
    - IRCAM - Benade, Max Mathews, and Pierre Boulez, 1975-1977 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - IRCAM - Scientific Advisory Committee, Paris July 13, 1977 (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - IRCAM - June 1978 (Box 131, Folder 3)
    - IRCAM - June 1979 (Box 131, Folder 4)
    - IRCAM - Boulez, Weinreich, and Schroeder, Meeting March 20-22, 1981 (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Jameson, George H. and Benade, Correspondence, 1969-1986 (Box 131, Folder 6)
    - Jameson, George H. and Benade. On the NX Clarinet Test; Jameson's Replacement Barrel Joint for Fred Cohen's Clarinet Pair; BCB Flute, (notes and correspondence), 1994-1995 (Box 131, Folder 7)
    - Discussion and Design Details on Benade's NX Clarinet, 1992-1994 (Box 131, Folder 8)
    - Benade's Mathematical "Compost Heap", 1983-1987 (Box 131, Folder 9)
    - Room-Averaged Spectra of Sample Notes of a Trumpet, Oboe, and Bassoon Notes, with Steve Lutgen, 1986-1987 (Box 131, Folder 10)
    - Peter Hoekye, Memorial Session Paper, 1988; Clarinet "Chops" Letters, Cubicciotti, Benade, Voxman, Jameson, 1983; Acoustics of Music, Benade's Pre Exams, 1981-1984 (Box 131, Folder 10)
    - Master Copies of Benade's Lecture Notes. Part I, (some with added comments or corrections), Included among these papers are most of Benade best. (Box 132, Folder 1)
    - Master Copies of Benade's Lecture Notes. Part II, (some with added comments or corrections) (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Benade, Physics Dept. Case Institute of Technology Computation Book, June 12, 1961 - Nov. 19, 1964 (Box 132, Folder 3)
    - John Cuddeback. Bound Notebook, (notes and calculations), 1972 (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - ASA Meeting anaheim, Dec. 8-12, 1986. Inquiry from Orchestral Musicians About Concert Halls. Presentation by Ian Lindevald with Comments by Robert Finn (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Bore Characteristic Effects; Flute - Family Regeneration Behavior. Response to Prof. O. K. Ledang; Bassoon, Calibrations, etc., 1980-1984 (Box 132, Folder 5)
    - Possible Retuning of Buffet Clarinets, 1976; Boehm-System Clarinet Pressure and Perturbation Measurements, 1980 (Box 132, Folder 6)
    - Oboe - Measurements and Drags:Triebert System-3 Zuleger 1037; Conservatory, 1981 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Clarinet - Measurements and Drags: Oehler System; Gerock 1837; Bassoon - Measurements and Drags: German System, 1980-1981 (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - Spectrum of "Quasi Square Wave," 1976; Clarinet Spectrum, 1980; Semiempirical spectrum Formula for Chotteau's Isospectrum Clarinet, 1982 (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Brass Instruments - Miscellaneous Correspondence., 1961-1966; Robert W. Young, on the Trumpet, 1967; Trumpet Bells, etc. with R. Kropfli, 1961; Trombone Bell Experiments, 1966; Bessel Horn Pressure Wave Functions, 1970 (Box 133, Folder 4)
    - The Horn - Curvature Measurements Devices, 1967; Measured Horn Bells, 1967-1968; Misc. 1972 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Erik Jannson, Correspondence and Research, 1966-1972 (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Piezo Electrical - CW: Calculations Notes and Data, Benade and Graudate Student, Ibisi, 1982-1985 (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Propagation in Tubes. Work with Benade's Research Assistant Gary Chanan, 1968 (Box 134, Folder 3)
    - Design Cylinder Head for a Boehm Flute, 1968; A Comparison of Boehm's Design of the Flute with that of Rockstro, by Walter W. Worman, 1969 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Report on Benade's Acoustical Research, 1968; George Jameson, 1969-1980; Howard Levine, 1984 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Acoustical Research - Original Manuscripts: Relative Frequencies of the Normal Modes of Bessel Horns, 1958; Modification of B and K Magnetic Transducer, 1966; Summary of Reflections at a Potential Wall, 1966; Reflection from a Potential step, 1966; Transmissions Through Barriers, 1966; Measurement of the Input Impedance of an Air Column, 1968; Wall Resonances of Pipes Excited by Plane Waves; Capillary Impedance Head, 1973 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - A Group of Computer Programs (Box 134, Folder 7)
    - Photographs (Box 134, Folder 8)
    - Benade's Equipment - Merhaut Impedance Head Apparatus and Accessories, 1988 (Box 135)
- Series 4. John Backus Collection, 1960-1990
  - Backus, John - Correspondence, 1963-1990; B1270-101 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    A research physicist who trained under E.O. Lawrence at the Berkeley Laboratories and later was on the faculty of the University of Southern California where he did research on gaseous discharges in strong magnetic fields. In addition he organized elementary courses in musical acoustics, thus bringing his special interests in music into the laboratory. He was a fine musician, playing the bassoon, clarinet and other woodwinds, the piano as well as conducting local orchestras. John received the Silver Medal of the ASA in 1986 for "pioneering research on the acoustics of woodwind and brass instruments and for bridging the gap between acousticians and musicians". John was an enthusiastic climber and holds the Sierra Club record for scaling 270 peaks six times. His textbook "Acoustical Foundations of Music" (W.W. Norton, 1969) was the first text in musical acoustics and was used widely.
    Correspondence: (42 from 1963-1990) involving mainly Backus and CMH. One piece involving Mrs. Saunders (Margaret T). Latest with Trisha and Robin Lamkie, daughter and son-in-law.
    Backus, John, 1911-1988
  - Backus, John - Clippings, Book Sleeve, and Christmas Cards, 1965-1987 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Backus, John - Technical, 1960-1978; B1270-103 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    17 technical papers from 1960-1978, most abstracted by Backus; detailed comments (197) by CMH for the revision of Backus' book. Topics: wind instruments; vibration modes, impedance; organ pipes; reeds.
  - Backus, John - Miscellaneous, 1986-1989; B1270-104 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    ASA Silver Medal Award materials and obituaries
  - Backus, John - Book Revisions, 1976-1977; B1270-105 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Backus' revisions; commentaries and suggestions by John C. Schelleng and CMH
  - Backus, John - Acoustical Foundations, 2nd Edition, 1977-1978; B1270-106 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Discussions with W.W. Norton on a second edition of Backus' book, Acoustical Foundations.
  - Backus, John - Brass Instruments, 1956-1968; B1270-107 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Resonance tests on trumpets; Paper by J. Edgar Young, "Timbre: An Investigation of French Horn Color; Paper by Malcolm C. Henderson "Thinking about Stopping: New Thoughts on a Horny Subject."
  - Backus, John - Fingering Charts, 1898-1927; B1270-108 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Fingering charts for the oboe, English horn, and Boehm clarinet
  - Backus, John - Resonance Frequencies of the Clarinet, 1967; B1270-109 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Correspondence and annotated abstracts on Backus' article, "Resonance Frequencies of the Clarinet"
  - Backus, John - Licensing of Graphite Reeds, 1984-1985; B1270-110 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Correspondence with Key Concepts on licensing Backus' graphite reeds.
    Removed legal size documents (Licensing Agreement) to box 60.
  - Backus, John - Drawings for Slides; Filters, undated; B1270-111 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Drawings, diagrams, graphs, and charts for slides; photographs (3); negatives (5) on Backus' studies on the trumpet and the clarinet.
  - Backus, John - Acoustics Notebooks III, IV, 1962-1964; hp390dh4085 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Notes, charts, and calculations for Backus' acoustical studies on the clarinet and trumpet, from Nov.30, 1962 - Dec.11, 1964.
  - Backus, John - Acoustics Notebooks V, VI, 1964-1966; dh189wd7964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Notes, charts, and calculations for Backus' acoustical experiments on the clarinet and trumpet, from Dec.26, 1964 - Apr.28, 1965.
  - Backus, John - Acoustics Notebook VII, 1966-1968; bv585gg7414 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Calculations, graphs, and notes pertaining mainly to measuring the clarinet's resonance using different kinds of reeds.
  - Backus, John - Acoustics Calculations III, IV, 1978-1981; qk805rq5724 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Calculations on: vibrating diaphragms; energy and power relations; Helmholtz resonator; impedance tube